# SHEM OGWENO

WEB DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

shemogweno.com

in linkedin.com/in/shemogweno

https://github.com/ogwenos

Rochester, NY

#### EDUCATION

## **BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND INFORMATION SECURITY**

Sept 2019 - Sept 2021 City University of New York, John Jay College

## **ASSOCIATES DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Jan 2017 - May 2019 Borough of Manhattan Community College

#### SKILLS

- Proficient in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, MySQL, HTML5, C#, JavaScript(ES6), CSS3, GraphQL
- Proficient in frameworks & libraries: React, Vue, Node.js, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Rspec
- Comfortable using: Linux, Windows, Mac OS
- Proficient in: Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Fullstack Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience.

I believe success is built through teamwork, collaboration and hard work, Always looking for opportunities to advance and grow my skills. Enjoy life long learning and coming up with creative solutions.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

January 2022 - Present

CatPrint.com - Fairport, NY

- Write clean and robust code for a diverse array of internal projects.
- Work with a variety of programming languages, and frameworks, and content management systems such as Ruby, React, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, CSS3, HTML5, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, Git, AWS, etc.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, Marketing team and Designers on a daily basis.

## WEB DEVELOPMENT MENTOR

December 2021 - Present

Volunteer - Remote

- Teach students remotely in web development using JavaScript, HTML & CSS
- Develop weekly lesson plans and projects to enhance the beginner learning experience, while creating landing page and portfolio

## **CAMERA OPERATOR & EDITOR**

May 2015 - March 2020

BRIC TV - New York, NY

- Story boarded and worked alongside the director to assist in directing and filming 'Chef Roulet' cooking show
- Filmed short documentaries and live TV productions.
- Trained and instructed assistant cameraman

#### **EDITOR & TRANSLATOR**

September 2017 - August 2018

The Documentary Group - New York, NY

Translated footage from Swahili to English for award-winning feature documentary: "When Lambs Become Lions"

#### REFERENCES

Available Upon Request